Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Strange Tales of Tang Dynasty III: To Chang'an]
[حكايات غريبة من سلالة تانغ الثالثة: إلى تشانغآن]
[Episode 9]
[الحلقة 9]
And since you injured Liu,
وبما أنك أذيت ليو،
I'm going to kill you!
سأقتلك!
Wait!
انتظر!
You can kill me,
يمكنك قتلي
but before you do it,
ولكن قبل أن تفعل ذلك،
please,
لو سمحت،
help me find this golden tablet.
ساعدني في العثور على هذا اللوح الذهبي.
It concerns the very fate of the Tang Empire.
ويتعلق الأمر بمصير إمبراطورية تانغ.
What golden tablet?
ما هو اللوح الذهبي؟
This golden tablet...
هذا اللوح الذهبي...
There's a thief on the rafters!
هناك لص على العوارض الخشبية!
Don't move!
لا تتحرك!
He must be the one who stole the golden tablet!
لا بد أنه هو من سرق اللوح الذهبي!
Catch him!
قبض عليه!
Using a hidden weapon against me?
استخدام سلاح مخفي ضدي؟
[Sublime Virtue]
[الفضيلة السامية]
I'm just a treasure hunter.
أنا مجرد صياد كنز.
The golden tablet is on me;
اللوح الذهبي عليّ؛
take it.
خذها.
[Wu Zhao, Sovereign of Zhou,]
[وو تشاو، ملك تشو]
[with the Taoist title Immortal Long-live of Lezhen Sect,]
[مع اللقب الطاوي الخالد طويل العمر من طائفة ليتشين]
[is humbly offering a golden tablet]
[يقدم بكل تواضع لوحًا ذهبيًا]
[on Mount Song, the Central Sacred Mountain,]
[على جبل سونغ، الجبل المقدس المركزي]
[praying to the Three Officials and Nine Courts]
[الصلاة إلى المسؤولين الثلاثة والمحاكم التسع]
[to absolve all of her sins.]
[ليغفر لها جميع ذنوبها]
My client said
قال موكلي
he'd pay me 10 gold coins for this golden tablet.
سيدفع لي 10 عملات ذهبية مقابل هذا اللوح الذهبي.
What's your client's name?
ما هو اسم عميلك؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
He dressed like a hermit,
كان يرتدي ملابس مثل الناسك،
with white hair and beard,
ذو شعر ولحية بيضاء،
but his face
لكن وجهه
looked quite young.
بدا صغيرا جدا.
How did you know?
كيف عرفت؟
Wu Zhao of Zhou?
وو تشاو تشو؟
This thing you're looking for
هذا الشيء الذي تبحث عنه
is no ordinary item.
ليس عنصرًا عاديًا.
If you find it,
إذا وجدته،
there will be 7 more coins waiting for you.
سيكون هناك 7 عملات معدنية أخرى في انتظارك.
If you already have so much gold,
إذا كان لديك بالفعل الكثير من الذهب،
why spend it
لماذا تنفقه
to find other gold?
للعثور على ذهب آخر؟
Even if the tablet is special,
حتى لو كان الجهاز اللوحي خاصًا،
it's still just made of gold.
إنه لا يزال مصنوعًا من الذهب فقط.
You treasure hunters
أنتم صائدو الكنوز
have one rule to follow—
لديك قاعدة واحدة يجب اتباعها -
ask only what the task is,
اسأل فقط ما هي المهمة،
not why.
ليس لماذا.
Otherwise...
خلاف ذلك...
Otherwise, we'll die.
وإلا فإننا سوف نموت.
[Treasure Hunter]
[صائد الكنز]
Forgive my prying.
سامحني على تطفلي.
I'll take the job.
سأقبل الوظيفة.
But...
لكن...
are you sure the treasure is in Chang'an?
هل أنت متأكد من أن الكنز موجود في تشانغآن؟
Yes.
نعم.
How do I contact you when I find it?
كيف يمكنني التواصل معك عندما أجده؟
You have one month.
لديك شهر واحد.
At the end of the month,
في نهاية الشهر،
meet me at the foot of Dayan Pagoda.
قابلني عند سفح معبد دايان.
[Law Before Power]
[القانون قبل القوة]
Is this him?
هل هذا هو؟
It's him.
إنه هو.
You must recall carefully
يجب عليك أن تتذكر بعناية
and provide us clues.
وتزويدنا بالدلائل.
That way you could redeem yourself through merit.
بهذه الطريقة يمكنك استرداد نفسك من خلال الجدارة.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
that day, when you were drinking at the restaurant,
في ذلك اليوم، عندما كنت تشرب في المطعم،
did anyone mention the Empress's affair?
هل ذكر أحد قضية الإمبراطورة؟
Yes.
نعم.
So I'm telling you,
لذلك أنا أقول لك،
what's recorded in the Chronicles of Shasi
ما هو مسجل في سجلات شاسي
is just the tip of the iceberg.
إنها مجرد قمة جبل الجليد.
I was completely captivated.
لقد كنت مفتونًا تمامًا.
[Law Before Power]
[القانون قبل القوة]
The hermit was so happy to hear that
كان الناسك سعيدًا جدًا لسماع ذلك
and even raised a toast to them.
وحتى رفع نخبًا لهم.
However,
لكن،
he might not have been genuinely happy.
ربما لم يكن سعيدًا حقًا.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
In our line of work,
في مجال عملنا،
observation is crucial.
الملاحظة أمر بالغ الأهمية.
I caught a glimpse of...
لقد ألقيت نظرة خاطفة على...
[Discipline and Service]
[الانضباط والخدمة]
Take him away.
خذه بعيدا.
Bring Mr. Tao in.
أحضر السيد تاو.
Move.
يتحرك.
Those who drank with him said
وقال الذين شربوا معه
Kuai Wu could really hold his liquor,
كان كواي وو قادرًا حقًا على احتواء مشروباته الكحولية،
so he couldn't have been drunk that night.
لذلك لا يمكن أن يكون مخمورا تلك الليلة.
Looks like whether he was drunk or not
يبدو أنه كان في حالة سكر أم لا
had nothing to do with his alcohol tolerance.
لم يكن له علاقة بتحمله للكحول.
The hermit must have drugged him.
لا بد أن الناسك قد أعطاه مخدرًا.
Kneel!
اركع!
Why are you treating an old man like that?
لماذا تعامل رجل عجوز بهذه الطريقة؟
He injured Liu.
لقد جرح ليو.
I'd kill him if I could!
سأقتله لو استطعت!
Did you hear that, Tao?
هل سمعت ذلك يا تاو؟
If you don't confess truthfully,
إذا لم تعترف بصدق،
you'll come to a bad end.
سوف تصل إلى نهاية سيئة.
[Discipline and Service]
[الانضباط والخدمة]
You turned your home into a temple,
لقد حوّلت منزلك إلى معبد،
and the purple-robed, handsome bearded man you worship
والرجل الوسيم ذو اللحية الأرجوانية الذي تعبده
looks much like Zhangsun Wuji.
إنه يشبه إلى حد كبير Zhangsun Wuji.
You even call him Duke Zhao when praying.
حتى أنك تناديه دوق تشاو عندما تصلي.
Then there's no mistake.
إذن لا يوجد خطأ.
The statues kneeling in front of him
التماثيل راكعة أمامه
must be Xu Jingzong, Li Yifu,
يجب أن يكون Xu Jingzong، Li Yifu.
and Yuan Gongyu.
ويوان قونغ يو.
Do you really think staying silent
هل تعتقد حقا أن البقاء صامتا
can hide who you are?
هل تستطيع إخفاء هويتك؟
You claim
أنت تدعي
this golden tablet
هذا اللوح الذهبي
concerns the fate of the Tang Empire.
يتعلق الأمر بمصير إمبراطورية تانغ.
Let me see
دعني أرى
what this is.
ما هذا؟
Wu Zhao, Sovereign of Zhou,
وو تشاو، ملك تشو،
[Discipline and Service]
[الانضباط والخدمة]
with the Taoist title Immortal Long-live of Lezhen Sect,
مع اللقب الطاوي الخالد طويل العمر من طائفة ليتشن،
is humbly offering a golden tablet
يقدم بكل تواضع لوحًا ذهبيًا
on Mount Song, the Central Sacred Mountain,
على جبل سونغ، الجبل المقدس المركزي،
praying to the Three Officials and Nine Courts
الصلاة إلى المسؤولين الثلاثة والمحاكم التسعة
to absolve all of her sins.
لتغفر لها جميع خطاياها.
In the year of Gengzi, the seventh lunar month,
في عام جنكزي، الشهر القمري السابع،
the seventh day.
اليوم السابع.
With the utmost respect
مع كل الاحترام
and humility,
والتواضع،
Hu Chao.
هو تشاو.
If I remember correctly,
إذا كنت أتذكر بشكل صحيح،
in the first year of Jiushi,
في السنة الأولى من جيوشي،
The Empress, still on the throne,
الإمبراطورة، لا تزال على العرش،
went to Sanyang Palace on Mount Shicong
ذهب إلى قصر سانيانغ على جبل شيكونغ
and ordered Daoist Hu Chao to climb Mount Song
وأمر الطاوي هو تشاو بتسلق جبل سونغ
and cast a golden tablet from Junji Peak
وألقى لوحًا ذهبيًا من قمة جونجي
to dispel misfortune
لتبديد المصائب
and cleanse her sins.
وتطهر من خطاياها.
This must be it.
يجب أن يكون هذا هو الأمر.
Why is it in your house,
لماذا هو في منزلك؟
weighed down by a stone?
مثقلة بحجر؟
Who exactly are you?
من أنت بالضبط؟
Jia.
جيا.
Bring a stool.
احضر مقعدًا.
Yes.
نعم.
Sit.
يجلس.
Now can you talk?
هل تستطيع التحدث الآن؟
My real name is Li Fengjie.
اسمي الحقيقي هو لي فينججي.
[Mr. Tao, Charcoal Seller]
[السيد تاو، بائع الفحم]
When I was young, I had a fiery temper
عندما كنت صغيرا، كان لدي مزاج ناري
[Li Fengjie, Old Courtier of the Eastern Capital]
[لي فينججي، الحاشية القديمة للعاصمة الشرقية]
and some skill in martial arts.
وبعض المهارات في فنون القتال.
Later, I roamed the capital
وفي وقت لاحق، تجولت في العاصمة
and accused an official of wrongdoing.
واتهم مسؤولا بارتكاب مخالفات.
That was about 50 years ago, wasn't it?
لقد كان ذلك منذ حوالي 50 عامًا، أليس كذلك؟
How do you know?
كيف علمت بذلك؟
My mentor, Master Di,
مرشدي، المعلم دي،
mentioned your name
ذكرت اسمك
while telling me about court affairs.
بينما كان يحدثني عن شؤون المحكمة.
I'm just a rogue.
أنا مجرد محتال.
I don't deserve to be mentioned
لا أستحق أن أذكر
by Master Di.
بقلم السيد دي.
When Emperor Gaozong was on the throne,
عندما كان الإمبراطور جاوزونغ على العرش،
the Empress wanted to remove
أرادت الإمبراطورة إزالة
Duke Zhao, Zhangsun Wuji.
الدوق تشاو، تشانغسون ووجي.
Her confidant Xu Jingzong
صديقها المقرب شو جينغزونغ
saw an opportunity
رأيت فرصة
and accused Duke Zhao
واتهم الدوق تشاو
of forming a faction
من تشكيل فصيل
with the official I accused,
مع المسؤول الذي اتهمته،
plotting rebellion,
التخطيط للتمرد،
and even asked me to fabricate evidence.
وحتى طلب مني أن أختلق الأدلة.
Later, Duke Zhao was demoted
في وقت لاحق، تم تخفيض رتبة الدوق تشاو
and forced to commit suicide,
وأجبروا على الانتحار،
and the Empress officially took power after that.
وتولت الإمبراطورة السلطة رسميًا بعد ذلك.
When the dust settled
عندما استقر الغبار
and I saw the truth,
ورأيت الحقيقة
I was full of regret.
لقد كنت مليئا بالندم.
I was afraid,
كنت خائفة
afraid of being silenced by villains,
خائف من أن يتم إسكاته من قبل الأشرار،
so I changed my name
لذلك غيرت اسمي
and became a coal seller.
وأصبح بائع الفحم.
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
I have regretted it
لقد ندمت على ذلك
constantly.
باستمرار.
I failed Duke Zhao
لقد فشلت مع الدوق تشاو
and brought harm to the Tang Empire.
وألحق الضرر بإمبراطورية تانغ.
So...
لذا...
you turned your house
لقد حولت منزلك
into a temple
إلى معبد
to worship Duke Zhao?
لعبادة الدوق تشاو؟
Yes.
نعم.
Since then,
منذ ذلك الحين،
I would rather stay in temples
أفضل البقاء في المعابد
than live in that house.
من العيش في هذا البيت.
I have no face
ليس لدي وجه
to share a home with Duke Zhao.
لمشاركة المنزل مع الدوق تشاو.
Where did you
أين كنت؟
get this golden tablet?
احصل على هذا اللوح الذهبي؟
It should have been thrown off
كان ينبغي أن يتم التخلص منه
Junji Peak on Mount Song
قمة جونجي على جبل سونغ
13 years ago.
منذ 13 سنة.
I got it 13 years ago.
لقد حصلت عليه منذ 13 عامًا.
Wu Zhao persecuted loyal officials
وو تشاو اضطهد المسؤولين الموالين
and then subverted the Tang Empire.
وبعد ذلك قاموا بتقويض إمبراطورية تانغ.
She wanted to use this golden tablet to dispel misfortune and cleanse her sins.
أرادت أن تستخدم هذا اللوح الذهبي لإزالة المصائب وتطهير خطاياها.
How could I let her succeed?
كيف يمكنني أن أسمح لها بالنجاح؟
I searched under the cliff
لقد بحثت تحت الجرف
for 49 days,
لمدة 49 يوما،
fought all kinds of dangerous animals,
حارب كل أنواع الحيوانات الخطيرة،
and finally
وأخيرا
found the golden tablet.
وجدت اللوح الذهبي.
I weighed it down with a stone from Mount Tai
لقد أثقلته بحجر من جبل تاي
and placed it before Duke Zhao's statue.
ووضعها أمام تمثال الدوق تشاو.
I wanted to make sure Wu Zhao
أردت التأكد من وو تشاو
would have no chance to atone
لن تكون هناك فرصة للتكفير
and rise again.
والنهوض مرة أخرى.
I understand your hatred
أنا أفهم كراهيتك
of the Empress,
من الإمبراطورة،
but why did you try to kill Wu Yang?
ولكن لماذا حاولت قتل وو يانغ؟
Kill Wu Yang?
قتل وو يانغ؟
I didn't.
لم أكن.
You still won't admit it?
هل لا تزال لن تعترف بذلك؟
I heard it with my own ears.
لقد سمعت ذلك بأذني.
Yes.
نعم.
I originally planned to kill Wu Yang,
لقد خططت في الأصل لقتل وو يانغ،
but I failed.
ولكنني فشلت.
For that,
من اجل ذلك،
I even stood before Duke Zhao's statue
حتى أنني وقفت أمام تمثال الدوق تشاو
to beg forgiveness.
لطلب المغفرة.
Why did you want to kill Wu Yang?
لماذا أردت قتل وو يانغ؟
Rumors in Chang'an say
تقول الشائعات في تشانغآن
the Empress will be reborn and take the throne again,
ستولد الإمبراطورة من جديد وتتولى العرش مرة أخرى،
and some even claim
وبعضهم حتى يدعي
Wu Zhao has already reincarnated
وو تشاو قد تجسد بالفعل
and she's right in Shengye District.
وهي في منطقة شينغي.
I searched all over Shengye District
لقد بحثت في جميع أنحاء منطقة شينغي
and discovered that Wu Yang
واكتشف أن وو يانغ
looks exactly like the Empress
يبدو تماما مثل الإمبراطورة
when she was young.
عندما كانت صغيرة.
I thought
اعتقدت
I had to kill her
كان علي أن أقتلها
to prevent the reincarnated Wu Zhao
لمنع تناسخ وو تشاو
from causing chaos in the Tang Empire again.
من التسبب في الفوضى في إمبراطورية تانغ مرة أخرى.
The concept of reincarnation is merely a fantasy.
إن مفهوم التناسخ هو مجرد خيال.
How could you believe it?
كيف تصدق ذلك؟
Besides,
بجانب،
the Empress passed away 8 years ago,
لقد توفيت الإمبراطورة منذ 8 سنوات،
while Wu Yang is 17 this year.
في حين يبلغ وو يانغ 17 عامًا هذا العام.
Her age doesn't match.
عمرها لا يتناسب.
I don't care about her age!
لا يهمني عمرها!
As long as she resembles the Empress,
طالما أنها تشبه الإمبراطورة،
I want her dead!
أريدها ميتة!
At 9 AM,
في الساعة 9 صباحًا،
let's meet at the entrance of the Chengfo Temple.
دعونا نلتقي عند مدخل معبد تشنغفو.
Okay.
تمام.
See you tomorrow then.
أراك غدا إذن.
I watched for days
لقد شاهدت لأيام
but never found an opportunity.
ولكن لم أجد الفرصة أبدًا.
Later I heard
سمعت لاحقا
that Wu Yang had disappeared.
أن وو يانغ قد اختفى.
Officer,
ضابط،
considering my advanced age,
بالنظر إلى عمري المتقدم،
please let me go.
من فضلك دعني أذهب.
You seriously wounded my constable,
لقد جرحت شرطي بشكل خطير،
which is already a crime.
وهو ما يعتبر جريمة بالفعل.
Moreover, because of rumors,
وعلاوة على ذلك، بسبب الشائعات،
you attempted to harm an innocent person,
لقد حاولت إيذاء شخص بريء،
which is unforgivable.
وهو أمر لا يغتفر.
Take him away.
خذه بعيدا.
Tell Yongzhou Prison
سجن تل يونغتشو
to keep him under strict guard.
لإبقائه تحت الحراسة المشددة.
-Yes.
-نعم.
Wait.
انتظر.
This isn't fair.
هذا ليس عادلا.
I want to know
أريد أن أعرف
where I slipped up
حيث انزلقت
so you could track me down.
حتى تتمكن من تعقبني.
Well, well, you old fellow.
حسنًا، حسنًا، أيها الرجل العجوز.
You look about my age.
أنت تبدو في مثل عمري.
You are a coal seller,
أنت بائع الفحم،
neither a fairy nor a beauty,
لا جنية ولا جميلة
so what are you doing with that
إذن ماذا تفعل بهذا؟
Fairy Beauty Powder?
بودرة الجمال الجنية؟
How...
كيف...
How did you know?
كيف عرفت؟
Let me tell you,
دعني أخبرك
my nose was a gift from the immortals.
كان أنفي هدية من الخالدين.
It's all my fault.
إنه خطئي كله.
To investigate Wu Yang
للتحقيق في وو يانغ
without arousing suspicion,
دون إثارة الشكوك،
I went into that shop
ذهبت إلى ذلك المتجر
and bought a box of Fairy Beauty Powder.
واشتريت صندوقًا من بودرة الجمال الجنية.
Then I couldn't bear to throw it away.
ثم لم أستطع أن أتحمل فكرة التخلص منه.
[Map of Chang'an City]
[خريطة مدينة تشانغآن]
See?
يرى؟
Right?
يمين؟
[Map of Chang'an City]
[خريطة مدينة تشانغآن]
Miss Pei.
السيدة باي.
I can do it myself.
أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك بنفسي.
Liu,
ليو،
no need to be so polite.
لا داعي لأن تكون مهذبا هكذا.
With your status,
مع حالتك،
I don't deserve this.
انا لا استحق هذا.
You were injured capturing a criminal. That is honorable.
لقد أُصبتَ أثناء القبض على مجرم. هذا أمرٌ مشرف.
You are a great hero.
أنت بطل عظيم.
By Master Fei's order, I prepared medicine
بأمر السيد فاي، قمت بإعداد الدواء
for a hero.
للبطل.
It's my honor.
إنه شرف لي.
Drink up.
اشرب.
I can
أنا استطيع
be considered a hero?
هل يعتبر بطلا؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
I've always felt
لقد شعرت دائما
I don't look heroic enough.
أنا لا أبدو بطوليًا بما فيه الكفاية.
If I had five strands of long beard,
لو كان لدي خمسة خصلات من اللحية الطويلة،
when I glare,
عندما أتحدق،
wouldn't I look
ألا ينبغي لي أن أنظر؟
a bit like Guan Yu?
شيء مثل جوان يو؟
Yes.
نعم.
Stick on a beard and you'll look even more like him.
أضف لحيتك وستبدو مثله أكثر.
A beard?
لحية؟
Chenkong!
تشينكونج!
It's that Chenkong!
إنه هذا تشنكونغ!
It's him!
إنه هو!
Householder Chenkong, the keeper of the Great Buddha Hall
رب الأسرة تشينكونغ، حارس قاعة بوذا العظيمة
in Chengfo Temple.
في معبد تشنغفو.
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكد؟
I felt he looked familiar
شعرت أنه يبدو مألوفا
the moment I first saw him.
اللحظة التي رأيته فيها لأول مرة.
I only just realized it now.
لقد أدركت ذلك الآن فقط.
I'm kicking myself.
أنا أركل نفسي.
He just glued on white hair and beard
لقد لصق فقط الشعر الأبيض واللحية
to disguise himself as a hermit.
لإخفاء نفسه في صورة ناسك.
Xijun is very sensitive
شيجون حساس للغاية
to people's appearances.
لمظهر الناس.
She shouldn't be wrong.
لا ينبغي لها أن تكون مخطئة.
[Chengfo Templea]
[معبد تشنغفو]
The reclining Buddha in the Great Buddha Hall
تمثال بوذا المتكئ في قاعة بوذا العظيمة
was initiated by Householder Chenkong
تم البدء بها من قبل رب الأسرة تشينكونغ
8 years ago.
منذ 8 سنوات.
He was also the largest donor.
وكان أيضًا المتبرع الأكبر.
Householder Chenkong has extraordinary bearing.
يمتلك رب الأسرة تشينكونغ سمعة غير عادية.
Do you know anything about his background?
هل تعرف شيئا عن خلفيته؟
[Great Buddha Hall]
[قاعة بوذا العظيمة]
Not much.
ليس كثيراً.
I only know his ancestral home is Luoyang.
كل ما أعرفه هو أن موطنه الأصلي هو لويانغ.
After Emperor Zhongzong's restoration,
بعد استعادة الإمبراطور تشونجزونغ،
he moved to Chang'an.
انتقل إلى تشانغآن.
He hasn't worked much over the years
لم يعمل كثيرًا على مر السنين
but is well off.
لكنها في وضع جيد.
A few months ago,
منذ بضعة أشهر،
he considered
لقد اعتبر
becoming a monk,
يصبح راهبًا،
but for some reason,
ولكن لسبب ما،
he changed his mind the next day.
لقد غير رأيه في اليوم التالي.
Official Lu.
لو الرسمي
Has Householder Chenkong, the keeper of the hall,
هل صاحب البيت تشنكونغ، حارس القاعة،
been here?
هل كنت هنا؟
No.
لا.
Since dawn, I've been the only one here
منذ الفجر، كنت الوحيد هنا
and haven't heard
ولم اسمع
any woman crying again.
أية امرأة تبكي مرة أخرى.
This young man has quite some courage.
هذا الشاب لديه قدر كبير من الشجاعة.
He's a hero indeed.
إنه بطل بالفعل.
What are you two whispering about?
ماذا تهمسون به؟
Where is Chenkong?
أين يقع تشينكونغ؟
He seems to have gone out last night.
يبدو أنه خرج الليلة الماضية.
Does he have a quarter to stay
هل لديه ربع للبقاء
in the temple?
في المعبد؟
Yes, yes.
نعم نعم.
Householder Chenkong, are you there?
سيد تشينكونغ، هل أنت هناك؟
The Yongzhou Prefecture has the authority
تتمتع محافظة يونغتشو بالسلطة
to enter directly when investigating a case.
للدخول مباشرة عند التحقيق في قضية ما.
What is he holding?
ماذا يحمل؟
Why is there a woman's comb...
لماذا يوجد مشط المرأة...
It looks like...
يبدو مثل...
In Householder Chenkong's room?
في غرفة رب البيت تشينكونغ؟
This looks like Wu Yang's comb.
يبدو هذا مثل مشط وو يانغ.
Can I be friends with you two?
هل يمكنني أن أكون صديقًا لكما؟
I don't have any friends.
ليس لدي أي أصدقاء.
-Of course.
-بالطبع.
Wu Yang.
وو يانغ.
The comb on your bun is so beautiful.
المشط الموجود على كعكة شعرك جميل جدًا.
She was indeed wearing
لقد كانت ترتدي بالفعل
this comb that day.
هذا المشط في ذلك اليوم.
Official Lu,
لو الرسمي
we found Householder Chenkong's trail
لقد وجدنا أثر رب الأسرة تشينكونغ
in Shengye District.
في منطقة شنغي.
I've already summoned
لقد استدعيت بالفعل
the Empress's spirit.
روح الإمبراطورة.
Now it's up to you.
الآن الأمر متروك لك.
Well?
حسنًا؟
Did you hear the Empress's voice?
هل سمعت صوت الإمبراطورة؟
No?
لا؟
Are you capable or not?
هل أنت قادر أم لا؟
I'm the best spirit medium
أنا أفضل وسيط روحي
in the entire Chang'an!
في تشانغآن بأكملها!
But whether you can meet the spirit
ولكن هل تستطيع أن تقابل الروح
depends on your sincerity.
يعتمد على صدقك.
Heaven and Earth can see my sincerity.
السماء والأرض يمكن أن ترى صدقي.
Very well!
جيد جدا!
Then I'll use another method—
ثم سأستخدم طريقة أخرى
to channel the Empress's spirit
لتوجيه روح الإمبراطورة
into my body
في جسدي
so she can speak to you.
حتى تتمكن من التحدث معك.
It's what people commonly call spirit possession.
إنه ما يطلق عليه الناس عادة اسم " استحواذ الروح".
Can you really do that?
هل يمكنك فعل ذلك حقا؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
But this technique
ولكن هذه التقنية
will consume more of my vital energy.
سوف تستهلك المزيد من طاقتي الحيوية.
You must give me two more gold coins.
يجب أن تعطيني عملتين ذهبيتين إضافيتين.
As long as
طالما
you can help me
يمكنك مساعدتي
meet with the Empress in the spirit realm,
الالتقاء بالإمبراطورة في عالم الأرواح،
I'll give you three.
سأعطيك ثلاثة.
I am the Empress.
أنا الإمبراطورة.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
It's me.
هذا أنا.
It's me!
هذا أنا!
Mr. Shen.
السيد شين.
I am Mr. Shen!
أنا السيد شين!
Mr. Shen?
السيد شين؟
Empress,
الإمبراطورة
don't you remember me?
ألا تتذكرني؟
I served by your side for
لقد خدمت بجانبك لمدة
more than 3 years.
أكثر من 3 سنوات.
How could I not remember you?
كيف لا أستطيع أن أتذكرك؟
When I showed you the slightest coldness,
عندما أظهرت لك أدنى قدر من البرودة،
you burned down Ming Hall.
لقد أحرقت قاعة مينغ.
Why are you trying to kill me?
لماذا تحاول قتلي؟
Don't you worship the Empress
ألا تعبد الإمبراطورة؟
above all?
فوق كل شيء؟
You fool!
يا أحمق!
You don't even know
أنت لا تعرف حتى
who burned the Ming Hall,
من أحرق قاعة مينغ،
yet you dared to cheat me out of money.
ولكنك تجرأت على خداعي وسرقة أموالي.
Go serve as a night watch in hell.
اذهب لتخدم كحارس ليلي في الجحيم.
There's blood on his hands.
هناك دماء على يديه.
I just killed a chicken.
لقد قتلت للتو دجاجة.
A chicken.
دجاجة.
Take him down.
خذه إلى الأسفل.
In the end she lost her life
وفي النهاية فقدت حياتها
over money.
على المال.
Chenkong did it.
تشنكونغ فعلها.
No! Not my face!
لا! ليس وجهي!
Don't hit my face!
لا تضرب وجهي!
Official Lu,
لو الرسمي
aren't you going to stop this?
ألن تتوقف عن هذا؟
Stop it! Stop!
توقف! توقف!
Let me.
دعني.
Yingtao! Yingtao!
ينجتاو! ينجتاو!
We need to interrogate him first.
نحن بحاجة إلى استجوابه أولاً.
Let's interrogate him first.
دعونا نستجوبه أولاً.
Why did you kill Ling, the night watch
لماذا قتلت لينج حارس الليل؟
of Shengye District?
من منطقة شينغي؟
She deserved it.
لقد استحقت ذلك.
Stupid as a pig.
غبي كالخنزير.
Xue Huaiyi was the one who burned Ming Hall.
شيو هوايي هو من أحرق قاعة مينغ.
My name is Shen Yu.
اسمي شين يو.
[Householder Chenkong]
[رب الأسرة تشنكونغ]
I don't mind being cheated out of money,
لا أمانع أن يتم الاحتيال عليّ من أجل الحصول على المال،
[Shen Yu, Wu Zetian's Former Favorite]
[شين يو، المفضل السابق لدى وو تسه تيان]
but she used the Empress's name to deceive me,
لكنها استخدمت اسم الإمبراطورة لخداعي،
so I had to kill her.
لذلك كان علي أن أقتلها.
So you are Shen Yu?
إذن أنت شين يو؟
I've heard a lot about you.
لقد سمعت الكثير عنك.
I should never have lived in this world.
لا ينبغي لي أن أعيش في هذا العالم أبدًا.
Back then,
في ذلك الوقت،
among those
من بين هؤلاء
self-righteous scholars,
العلماء المتعصبين
my name was a disgrace.
كان اسمي عارًا.
But I didn't care.
ولكنني لم أهتم.
The 3 years beside the Empress
السنوات الثلاث بجانب الإمبراطورة
were the best
كانوا الأفضل
of my life.
من حياتي.
It was you
لقد كنت انت
who took Wu Yang
من أخذ وو يانغ
from the backyard of Yu Residence?
من الفناء الخلفي لمنزل يو؟
Now,
الآن،
where is she?
أين هي؟
Is she alive?
هل هي على قيد الحياة؟
I don't know where she is.
لا أعرف أين هي.
This was found in your quarter.
لقد تم العثور على هذا في حيك.
We've already had Wu Yang's mother identify it.
لقد تمكنا بالفعل من التعرف على والدة وو يانغ.
Are you still going to deny it?
هل ستستمر في الإنكار؟
Fake hermit!
الناسك المزيف!
Fake householder!
رب منزل مزيف!
What have you done to Wu Yang?
ماذا فعلت لوو يانغ؟
I'll kill you!
سأقتلك!
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
Fake householder!
رب منزل مزيف!
Fake hermit!
الناسك المزيف!
Give me back Wu Yang!
أعطني وو يانغ!
Chi Ying!
تشي ينغ!
We all understand how you feel.
نحن جميعا نفهم كيف تشعر.
But we're in the middle of questioning him
لكننا في منتصف استجوابه
and the truth hasn't been revealed yet.
ولم يتم الكشف عن الحقيقة بعد
You're yelling in court
أنت تصرخ في المحكمة
and attempting to commit murder!
ومحاولة ارتكاب جريمة قتل!
What kind of behavior is this?
ما هذا النوع من السلوك؟
I want him to return Wu Yang to me!
أريد منه أن يعيد لي وو يانغ!
What have you done to Wu Yang?
ماذا فعلت لوو يانغ؟
Fake hermit!
الناسك المزيف!
-Fake householder! -Calm down.
- رب منزل مزيف! - اهدأ.
Give me back Wu Yang!
أعطني وو يانغ!
Go! Go!
إذهب! إذهب!
Let me go! Give me back Wu Yang!
دعني أذهب! أعطني وو يانغ!
You still won't talk?
هل لازلت لا تريد التحدث؟
Where is Wu Yang?
أين وو يانغ؟
I truly don't know where Wu Yang is.
أنا حقا لا أعرف أين وو يانغ.
Then how did this comb
ثم كيف تم هذا المشط
end up in your hands?
ينتهي في يديك؟
Just put me in jail already.
لقد وضعوني في السجن بالفعل.
Official Lu,
لو الرسمي
how about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
Let's all go
دعونا نذهب جميعا
and leave him with Madam Yingtao
وتركه مع السيدة ينغتاو
and Chi Ying.
وتشي ينغ.
They
هم
will tear your face apart.
سوف يمزق وجهك.
No! No!
لا لا!
Don't!
لا!
Don't let them hit my face.
لا تدعهم يضربون وجهي.
Otherwise, the Empress won't recognize me.
وإلا فإن الإمبراطورة لن تتعرف علي.
Then tell us the truth.
ثم أخبرنا الحقيقة.
I truly don't know
انا حقا لا اعرف
where Wu Yang is.
أين وو يانغ.
The first time I saw Wu Yang
المرة الأولى التي رأيت فيها وو يانغ
was at Chengfo Temple.
كان في معبد تشنغفو.
At that time,
في ذلك الوقت،
I had already decided to become a monk.
لقد قررت بالفعل أن أصبح راهبًا.
Buddhist Guangxiao agreed
وافق البوذي قوانغشياو
to shave my head the next day.
لأحلق رأسي في اليوم التالي.
Amitabha.
أميتابها.
[Great Buddha Hall]
[قاعة بوذا العظيمة]
Back then,
في ذلك الوقت،
I was summoned into the palace
لقد تم استدعائي إلى القصر
as an imperial physician by the Empress.
كطبيب إمبراطوري من قبل الإمبراطورة.
I couldn't see
لم أستطع الرؤية
the Empress every day.
الإمبراطورة كل يوم.
So the Empress
لذلك الإمبراطورة
rewarded me with a portrait of her younger self.
كافأني بصورة لها عندما كانت أصغر سنا.
I needed to look at it 1000 times a day.
كان يجب علي أن أنظر إليه 1000 مرة في اليوم.
Wu Yang looks just like her.
وو يانغ تبدو تمامًا مثلها.
No,
لا،
not just like her.
ليس مثلها فقط.
She is the Empress herself.
إنها الإمبراطورة نفسها.
Later, because the two Zhangs gained favor,
وفي وقت لاحق، لأن الزوجين تشانغ اكتسبا تأييدًا،
I left the palace.
غادرت القصر.
But my heart
ولكن قلبي
never left the Empress.
لم يغادر الإمبراطورة أبدًا.
The year the Empress passed away,
في العام الذي توفيت فيه الإمبراطورة،
I came to Chang'an
لقد جئت إلى تشانغآن
and built her favorite reclining Buddha
وبنت تمثال بوذا المتكئ المفضل لديها
at Chengfo Temple,
في معبد تشنغفو،
because I wanted
لأنني أردت
to always be by her side.
أن أكون بجانبها دائمًا.
But unexpectedly,
ولكن بشكل غير متوقع،
the Buddha granted my wish
لقد حقق بوذا أمنيتي
and reunited me with the Empress.
وأعادني إلى الإمبراطورة.
I immediately gave up my ordination.
لقد تخليت عن رسامتي على الفور.
I wanted to return
أردت العودة
to the Empress's side.
إلى جانب الإمبراطورة.
Wu Yang.
وو يانغ.
The wind's picking up— looks like rain's coming.
بدأت الرياح تشتد - ويبدو أن المطر قادم.
Let's be quick about it
دعونا نكون سريعين في هذا الشأن
and close up for the day.
وأغلق لهذا اليوم.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
But the Empress was reincarnated as Wu Yang
لكن الإمبراطورة تجسدت مرة أخرى في وو يانغ
and didn't recognize me.
ولم يتعرف علي.
And Chi Ying was watching her closely,
وكانت تشي ينغ تراقبها عن كثب،
so I had to disguise myself
لذلك كان علي أن أتنكر
to get close to her.
للتقرب منها.
Old sir,
سيدي العجوز،
are you all right?
هل انت بخير؟
Do I look that old to you?
هل أبدو لك بهذا العمر؟
Seeing you
رؤيتك
reminded me of someone I once knew.
ذكّرني بشخص كنت أعرفه ذات يوم.
You look so much like her.
أنت تشبهها كثيرًا.
Who is she?
من هي؟
My former lover.
حبيبتي السابقة.
Since that day,
منذ ذلك اليوم،
I've been unable to sleep.
لم أتمكن من النوم.
Wu Yang,
وو يانغ،
take good care of the shop.
اعتني بالمتجر جيدًا.
I'll be back soon.
سأعود قريبا.
After that,
بعد ذلك،
I tried every possible way
لقد حاولت بكل الطرق الممكنة
to get close to Wu Yang,
للتقرب من وو يانغ،
even if it was
حتى لو كان
just to catch a glimpse from afar
فقط لإلقاء نظرة من بعيد
or
أو
send her letters.
أرسل لها رسائل.
[Meixiu Skincare Shop]
[متجر Meixiu للعناية بالبشرة]
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Come on.
تعال.
What do you mean
ماذا تقصد
by "send letters?"
"إرسال رسائل؟"
Did Wu Yang ever write back to you?
هل كتب لك وو يانغ ردًا على الإطلاق؟
Yes, she did.
نعم لقد فعلت ذلك.
She said her mother
قالت أمها
watched her too closely
راقبتها عن كثب
and that she wanted to follow me
وأنها تريد أن تتبعني
to wander through the landscapes of the Tang Empire.
للتجول عبر المناظر الطبيعية لإمبراطورية تانغ.
I had
لقد كان لدي
already won her heart,
لقد فاز بالفعل بقلبها،
but because...
ولكن لأن...
[Great Buddha Hall]
[قاعة بوذا العظيمة]
Amitabha.
أميتابها.
I usually don't grow a beard,
أنا عادة لا أربي لحيتي،
because I'm afraid the Empress
لأني أخشى أن الإمبراطورة
wouldn't recognize me
لن يتعرف علي
in my dreams.
في أحلامي.
I disguised myself as a hermit
لقد تنكرت في صورة ناسك
just to get close to Wu Yang.
فقط للتقرب من وو يانغ.
I thought
اعتقدت
I could explain everything
يمكنني أن أشرح كل شيء
once we got familiar.
بمجرد أن أصبحنا مألوفين.
But
لكن
she wrote back
كتبت ردا
that she didn't want
انها لا تريد
any contact with someone
أي اتصال مع شخص ما
who had deceived her.
الذي خدعها.
No matter how I tried to explain,
بغض النظر عن كيفية محاولتي للشرح،
she refused to reply again.
رفضت الرد مرة أخرى.
So,
لذا،
you kidnapped Wu Yang?
هل اختطفت وو يانغ؟
I...
أنا...
I did think about it,
لقد فكرت في هذا الأمر،
but before I could act,
ولكن قبل أن أتمكن من التصرف،
someone beat me to it.
لقد سبقني شخص ما إلى ذلك.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Bravo! Bravo! Bravo!
برافو! برافو! برافو!
Bravo!
برافو!
Then you followed them
ثم تبعتهم
to the back garden of a residence,
إلى الحديقة الخلفية للمنزل،
used slumbering incense to knock out the guards,
استخدم البخور النائم لضرب الحراس،
and took Wu Yang away.
وأخذ وو يانغ بعيدا.
So you know?
هل تعلم؟
Come, keep drinking.
تعال، استمر في الشرب.
Fill the cup.
إملأ الكأس.
Empress,
الإمبراطورة
I am Mr. Shen.
أنا السيد شين.
Since your ascension,
منذ صعودك،
I've been thinking of you day and night.
لقد كنت أفكر بك ليلًا ونهارًا.
Today,
اليوم،
you're finally back.
لقد عدت أخيرا.
Insane.
مجنون.
You're insane!
أنت مجنون!
Has no one
ليس لديه أحد
ever told you that you look like the Empress?
هل سبق وأن قلت لك أنك تشبه الإمبراطورة؟
Of course they have.
بالطبع لديهم.
That's been my biggest annoyance
لقد كان هذا أكبر إزعاج لي
for years.
لسنوات.
I thought your appearance
اعتقدت أن مظهرك
was destined.
كان مقدرا.
I didn't expect you had ulterior motives too.
لم أتوقع أن لديك دوافع خفية أيضًا.
I never want to see you again.
لا أريد رؤيتك مرة أخرى أبدًا.
Let me go,
دعني أذهب
or I'll report you to the authorities.
أو سأبلغ عنك للسلطات.
She was so resolute.
لقد كانت حازمة للغاية.
I thought
اعتقدت
the only way to awaken her memories
الطريقة الوحيدة لإيقاظ ذكرياتها
of her past life was to bring her
من حياتها الماضية كان من أجل جلبها
before the giant Buddha built for her.
قبل أن يبني لها تمثال بوذا العملاق.
What if she refused?
ماذا لو رفضت؟
Then there was nothing I could do.
وبعد ذلك لم يعد هناك شيء أستطيع فعله.
No!
لا!
[Map of Chang'an City]
[خريطة مدينة تشانغآن]
You just want her
أنت فقط تريدها
to stay inside the Buddha forever,
للبقاء داخل بوذا إلى الأبد،
merging Wu Yang
دمج وو يانغ
with the giant Buddha you financed.
مع تمثال بوذا العملاق الذي قمت بتمويله.
Official Lu has already discovered
لقد اكتشف المسؤول لو بالفعل
the stone coffin you carved behind the Buddha.
التابوت الحجري الذي نحتته خلف بوذا.
Two months ago,
منذ شهرين،
late at night at Chengfo Temple,
في وقت متأخر من الليل في معبد تشنغفو،
cries of a woman were suddenly heard.
وفجأة سمعنا صراخ امرأة.
And you fabricated lies,
واختلقت الاكاذيب
claiming the Buddha appeared in your dream
ادعاء ظهور بوذا في حلمك
and using dust and cobwebs
واستخدام الغبار وأنسجة العنكبوت
to trap the Subjugation of Devils,
للإيقاع باستعباد الشياطين،
all just to scare others away
كل هذا فقط لتخويف الآخرين
from the Great Buddha Hall
من قاعة بوذا العظيم
so you could carve the stone coffin, right?
حتى تتمكن من نحت التابوت الحجري، أليس كذلك؟
What was that woman's crying
ماذا كانت تبكي تلك المرأة؟
really about?
حقا عن؟
Have you killed
هل قتلت
other girls too?
الفتيات الأخريات أيضا؟
You'll never know.
لن تعرف أبدا.
You're overconfident.
أنت واثق من نفسك أكثر من اللازم.
The truth will come out.
الحقيقة ستظهر
Wasn't it just a trick
ألم تكن مجرد خدعة؟
of Night-Wandering Ladies?
من السيدات المتجولات في الليل؟
What's a Night-Wandering Lady?
ما هي السيدة المتجولة في الليل؟
It's a kind of bird,
إنه نوع من الطيور
said to be
يقال أنه
transformed from deceased women who died in childbirth.
تم تحويلها من النساء المتوفيات اللاتي توفين أثناء الولادة.
That's why they like to secretly snatch babies
لهذا السبب يحبون اختطاف الأطفال سراً
and often cry miserably
وغالبا ما تبكي بشدة
at night.
في الليل.
Their cries sound like a woman weeping.
صراخهم يشبه بكاء المرأة.
Yesterday, Yingtao saw a hole in the roof
بالأمس، رأى ينغتاو ثقبًا في السقف
of the Great Buddha Hall.
قاعة بوذا العظيم.
Early this morning, she sent people
في وقت مبكر من هذا الصباح، أرسلت الناس
to set up a ladder to check it out,
لإعداد سلم للتحقق من ذلك،
and they immediately caught
وأمسكوا به على الفور
5 or 6 of these Night-Wandering Ladies.
5 أو 6 من هؤلاء السيدات المتجولات في الليل.
It's a nest of little birds.
إنه عش الطيور الصغيرة.
Bring one down.
احضر واحدا.
This kind of bird
هذا النوع من الطيور
only roosts deep in the mountains.
لا يتواجد إلا في أعماق الجبال.
Even if it flies into the city during the day,
حتى لو طارت إلى المدينة أثناء النهار،
it always returns at night.
إنه يعود دائمًا في الليل.
But now it's nesting in the Great Buddha Hall.
لكن الآن هو يعشش في قاعة بوذا العظيمة.
Clearly,
بوضوح،
someone did this on purpose.
لقد فعل شخص ما هذا عمدا.
These birds
هذه الطيور
fly at night and hide during the day.
يطير في الليل ويختبئ أثناء النهار.
They love the dark and fear the light,
إنهم يحبون الظلام ويخافون النور.
so once daylight comes,
لذا بمجرد أن يأتي ضوء النهار،
they stop crying.
توقفوا عن البكاء.
I see.
أرى.
That day I heard the cries,
في ذلك اليوم سمعت الصراخ،
but the moment Lu Lingfeng lit his fire striker,
ولكن في اللحظة التي أشعل فيها لو لينغفينغ مضربه الناري،
they stopped.
لقد توقفوا.
That explains it.
وهذا ما يفسر ذلك.
I remember now.
انا أتذكر الآن.
Those who often go to Mount Zhongnan to gather herbs
أولئك الذين يذهبون غالبًا إلى جبل تشونغنان لجمع الأعشاب
in the Ghost Market
في سوق الأشباح
always carry
احمل دائما
a few of these strange birds with them.
بعض من هذه الطيور الغريبة معهم.
Back to the point.
العودة إلى النقطة.
Where is Wu Yang?
أين وو يانغ؟
I spent two months
لقد قضيت شهرين
carving behind the Buddha.
نحت خلف بوذا.
Yes,
نعم،
I wanted the Buddha's golden body
أردت جسد بوذا الذهبي
and Wu Yang's mortal body to merge,
ودمج جسد وو يانغ البشري،
so I could better summon
حتى أتمكن من استدعاء أفضل
the Empress's soul.
روح الإمبراطورة.
I also learned one thing.
لقد تعلمت شيئا واحدا أيضا.
The golden tablet that the Empress
اللوح الذهبي الذي وضعته الإمبراطورة
had Taoist Hu Chao offer to the gods
كان الطاوي هو تشاو يقدم عرضًا للآلهة
atop Mount Song as atonement back then
على قمة جبل سونغ كتكفير في ذلك الوقت
was stolen.
لقد سُرقت.
It's now in Chang'an.
إنه الآن في تشانغآن.
So I hired a treasure hunter.
لذلك قمت بتعيين صائد الكنز.
I thought that
اعتقدت ذلك
once I obtained the golden tablet,
بمجرد حصولي على اللوح الذهبي،
I would hide it inside the Buddha as well.
سأخفيه داخل بوذا أيضًا.
Then,
ثم،
I would become a monk
سأصبح راهبًا
and spend the rest of my life guarding her.
وأقضي بقية حياتي في حراستها.
Are you talking about
هل تتحدث عن
this golden tablet?
هذا اللوح الذهبي؟
[It says, "Wu Zhao, Sovereign of Zhou,]
[يقول، "وو تشاو، حاكم تشو،]
[with the Taoist title Immortal Long-live of Lezhen Sect,]
[مع اللقب الطاوي الخالد طويل العمر من طائفة ليتشين]
[is humbly offering a golden tablet]
[يقدم بكل تواضع لوحًا ذهبيًا]
[on Mount Song, the Central Sacred Mountain,]
[على جبل سونغ، الجبل المقدس المركزي]
[praying to the Three Officials and Nine Courts]
[الصلاة إلى المسؤولين الثلاثة والمحاكم التسع]
[to absolve all of her sins."]
"[ليغفر لها جميع ذنوبها."
[In the year of Gengzi, the seventh lunar month, the seventh day.]
[في عام جنكزي، الشهر القمري السابع، اليوم السابع.]
[With the utmost respect and humility, Hu Chao]
[مع أقصى درجات الاحترام والتواضع، هو تشاو]
[Law Before Power]
[القانون قبل القوة]
I, Shen Yu,
أنا، شين يو،
pay my respects to you, Empress!
أتقدم إليك باحتراماتي، أيها الإمبراطورة!
[Map of Chang'an City]
[خريطة مدينة تشانغآن]
Xue Huan.
شيويه هوان.
Confess your crimes now!
اعترف بجرائمك الآن!
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Let go of me!
أتركني!
Behave yourself.
أحسن التصرف.
[Great Buddha Hall]
[قاعة بوذا العظيمة]
Come home tonight.
تعال إلى المنزل الليلة.
Please bless my daughter.
من فضلك بارك ابنتي.
Let her come home tonight.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الليلة.
Let her come home now.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الآن.
Buddha,
بوذا،
please bless my daughter.
من فضلك بارك ابنتي.
Let her come home now.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الآن.
Let her come home tonight.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الليلة.
Bless my daughter.
بارك الله في ابنتي.
-Let her come home tonight. -Chi Ying?
-دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الليلة. -تشي ينغ؟
Let her come home now.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الآن.
Buddha, please
بوذا من فضلك
-bless my daughter. -Chi Ying.
-بارك الله في ابنتي. -تشي ينغ.
This hall is sealed.
هذه القاعة مغلقة.
No worshiping is allowed at night.
لا يجوز العبادة في الليل.
You should go home.
ينبغي عليك أن تذهب إلى المنزل.
When they built this Buddha,
عندما بنوا هذا بوذا،
I donated 5,000 coins.
لقد تبرعت بـ 5000 قطعة نقدية.
I can worship whenever I want.
أستطيع أن أعبد متى شئت.
That was the agreement.
هذا كان الاتفاق.
Now my daughter is missing.
الآن ابنتي مفقودة.
Only this Buddha knows
هذا بوذا فقط يعرف
where she is.
أين هي.
Buddha, please bless her.
بوذا، من فضلك باركها.
Bless my daughter.
بارك الله في ابنتي.
Let her come home tonight.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الليلة.
Let her come home now.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الآن.
Bless my daughter.
بارك الله في ابنتي.
Let her come home tonight.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الليلة.
Let her come home now.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الآن.
Bless my daughter.
بارك الله في ابنتي.
Chi Ying was praying
تشي ينغ كانت تصلي
and Mr. Tao was asleep.
وكان السيد تاو نائما.
Neither of them would leave.
لا أحد منهما يريد المغادرة.
So I had no choice but to blow out the candles
لذلك لم يكن أمامي خيار سوى إطفاء الشموع
and try to scare them off using the birds.
وحاول تخويفهم باستخدام الطيور.
Bless my daughter.
بارك الله في ابنتي.
Buddha, please bless her.
بوذا، من فضلك باركها.
Let her come home tonight.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الليلة.
Let her come home now.
دعها تأتي إلى المنزل الآن.
Buddha, please bless her.
بوذا، من فضلك باركها.
Wu Yang!
وو يانغ!
But I failed.
ولكنني فشلت.
[Great Buddha Hall]
[قاعة بوذا العظيمة]
It wasn't until 3 AM
لم يكن حتى الساعة 3 صباحًا
that I finally coaxed Chi Ying to leave
أنني أقنعت تشي ينغ أخيرًا بالمغادرة
and drove Mr. Tao out of Chengfo Temple.
وأخرج السيد تاو من معبد تشنغفو.
Wu Yang,
وو يانغ،
come on, look.
تعال، انظر.
This is the Buddha
هذا هو بوذا
I specially built for you.
لقد بنيت خصيصا لك.
How do you like it?
كيف تريده ؟
Do you remember who I am now?
هل تتذكر من أنا الآن؟
Lunatic!
مجنون!
It seems the Empress's spirit within you
يبدو أن روح الإمبراطورة بداخلك
hasn't awakened yet.
لم يستيقظ بعد
It doesn't matter.
لا يهم.
I can wait.
انا استطيع الانتظار.
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
I'll take you to your hometown,
سأأخذك إلى مسقط رأسك
Wenshui in Bingzhou.
(وينشوي في بينجتشو).
There,
هناك،
I'll make you
سأجعلك
my empress, mine alone.
امبراطورتي، امبراطورتي وحدي.
Okay?
تمام؟
Dream on.
إحلم.
If you don't agree,
إذا كنت لا توافق،
I'll have no choice but to kill you.
لن يكون لدي خيار سوى قتلك.
Death itself isn't frightening;
الموت في حد ذاته ليس مخيفا؛
what's frightening
ما هو المخيف
is being alive and being bound.
أن تكون على قيد الحياة وأن تكون مقيدًا.
In that moment,
في تلك اللحظة،
I hesitated.
لقد ترددت.
She was so calm,
لقد كانت هادئة جداً
as if her heart
وكأن قلبها
could hold mountains and rivers
يمكن أن تحتوي على الجبال والأنهار
and contain floods and beasts.
وتحتوي على الفيضانات والوحوش.
She truly is the Empress!
إنها حقا الإمبراطورة!
Tell me,
أخبرني،
how could I bear to kill her?
كيف أستطيع أن أتحمل قتلها؟
It's you?
هل انت؟
In a daze,
في حالة ذهول،
I saw someone
لقد رأيت شخص ما
take Wu Yang away.
خذ وو يانغ بعيدًا.
I wanted to chase after him,
أردت أن أطارده،
but I had no strength at all.
ولكن لم تكن لدي أي قوة على الإطلاق.
Then,
ثم،
I blacked out,
لقد فقدت الوعي
until this young lady
حتى هذه الشابة
came into the Great Buddha Hall.
دخلت إلى قاعة بوذا العظيمة.
[Law Before Power]
[القانون قبل القوة]
I blame myself for not recognizing you sooner,
ألوم نفسي لعدم التعرف عليك في وقت سابق،
which let you keep doing evil
الذي يسمح لك بالاستمرار في فعل الشر
and killing Auntie Ling.
وقتل العمة لينغ.
There's another murder case—
هناك قضية قتل أخرى
Kuai Wu.
كواي وو.
He...
هو...
deserved to die even more!
استحق الموت أكثر!
He dared to publicly
لقد تجرأ على ذلك علناً
slander the Empress!
افتراء على الإمبراطورة!
I simply offered him a cup of wine
لقد عرضت عليه ببساطة كوبًا من النبيذ
with a bit of poison in it.
مع قليل من السم فيه.
I didn't drink much today,
لم أشرب الكثير اليوم،
but why am I...
ولكن لماذا انا...
so terribly drunk?
هل أنت في حالة سكر شديدة؟
I did this with great satisfaction.
لقد فعلت هذا برضا كبير.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
I'll kill whoever dares
سأقتل كل من يجرؤ
to slander the Empress
لتشويه سمعة الإمبراطورة
without hesitation.
بدون تردد.
Shen Yu, oh, Shen Yu,
شين يو، أوه، شين يو،
You entered the palace as an imperial physician.
لقد دخلت القصر كطبيب إمبراطوري.
But now,
ولكن الآن،
what you're doing is murder.
ما تفعله هو القتل.
You are simply a disgrace
أنت مجرد عار
to the word "physician!"
إلى كلمة "طبيب!"
My face!
وجهي!
[Law Before Power]
[القانون قبل القوة]
Official Lu, Scholar Su.
لو الرسمي، الباحث سو.
A female corpse was found in the Ghost Market,
تم العثور على جثة امرأة في سوق الأشباح،
similar in age to Wu Yang.
مماثل في العمر لـ وو يانغ.